<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/consulting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Vincent Giles, an Australian composer born in 1985 and based in Naarm (Melbourne). My work explores the fragile boundaries of perception, the beauty in instability, and those fascinating glitches that emerge from both human and machine creativity.&#xA;My music has traveled across North America, Europe, South-East Asia, and throughout Australia, brought to life by incredible performers like Peter Sheridan, Lizzy Welsh, Alice Bennett, Halfsound, Arcko Symphonic Ensemble, and Fragments Ensemble. You might have heard my work at the Darmstädter Ferienkurse, Tura Totally Huge New Music Festival, various Fringe Festivals in Melbourne, Sydney and Newcastle, or during the Impulse Festival and Academy for New Music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition &amp; Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/composition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My music has been performed by collaborators like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marriedflutes.net/&#34;&gt;Peter Sheridan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lizzywelsh.com/&#34;&gt;Lizzy Welsh&lt;/a&gt;, and Fragments Ensemble across North America, Europe, Asia, and Australia, at festivals from &lt;em&gt;Darmstädter Ferienkurse&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Tura’s Totally Huge New Music Festival&lt;/em&gt;. The scores themselves are published by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.australiancomposers.com&#34;&gt;Wirripang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edition-resonance.xyz&#34;&gt;Edition Resonance&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.australianmusiccentre.com.au&#34;&gt;Australian Music Centre&lt;/a&gt;, and reach new audiences around the world. I&amp;rsquo;m driven by collaboration, and indeed, have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridgescholars.com/product/978-1-5275-0577-3&#34;&gt;written about the importance of that&lt;/a&gt;, and whether written for baroque instruments, improvising ensembles, or autonomous computer agents, I believe my best work comes out with other people. It’s why I co-founded Tilde: to create spaces for new collaborations to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshops &amp; Public Speaking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With nearly two decades of music education experience—including ten years in tertiary institutions like the Australian Institute of Music, Monash University, and Collarts—I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of mentoring emerging artists who now thrive in their own creative careers. My approach blends rigorous training with the kind of real-world insights that only come from active artistic practice. I regularly share my perspective on creative practice through invited talks at:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Community arts groups, like MediaLab Melbourne and Banyule City Council&amp;rsquo;s Arts and Culture programme&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Academic spaces, such as the University of Melbourne and Bio 21 Laboratory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Regional community arts spaces, like Julia St Creative Space on the South-West coast of Victoria.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I co-founded &lt;em&gt;Tilde New Music and Sound Art Inc.&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alicebennett.net&#34;&gt;Alice Bennett&lt;/a&gt;, serving as co-director until 2020. Tilde was dedicated to public presentation and education of avant-garde music in the Oceanic region. This work culminated in a major eight-day festival, backed by over $100,000 in funding, which brought together panel discussions on equity in new music, cross-disciplinary performances across multiple venues, and our signature artist development academy. What began as a passion project grew into an organization that shaped conversations about music&amp;rsquo;s evolving role in our culture—while giving me the chance to both teach in our academies and present my own creative work, and addressing a significant gap in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
